Guide to the Harold Ober Associates Letters
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Harold Ober Associates Letters
1933-1977.
Harold Ober Associates.
4.5 linear ft. (circa 7,250 items in 9 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library,
4079172
This collection consists of correspondence between Harold Ober and Paul Gallico. It includes correspondence concerning Gallico and his work.
Historical Note
Literary agency.
Scope and Content
Files of correspondence containing more than 1,000 letters from Gallico and over 4,500 letters to Gallico from Harold Ober. There is also correspondence concerning Gallico. These files discuss literary works in progress, plans for future articles and books, contracts and financial agreements, and screenplays of his novels.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: Correspondence
Subjects
Gallico, Paul, 1897-1976.; Ober, Harold.; Motion picture plays.; Literature--Adaptations.; Authors.; Literature publishing.; Literary agents.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1969 M-69 Harold Ober Associates, Inc. Gift
Related Material
See also the finding aid for the Paul Gallico Papers.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - 1933-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1946 (Box 2)
  - 1947-1951 (Box 3)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 4)
  - 1955-1959 and MCA Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 5)
  - 1960-1964 (Box 6)
  - 1965-1967 (Correspondence Concerning; no letters from Gallico) (Box 7)
  - 1970-1973 (Box 8)
  - 1974-1977 (Box 9)